A Guide to the Staunton Photographic Collection 1910-1921
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Staunton Photographic Collection 1910-1921
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11156
There are 91 photographs.
There are ninety-one photographs, 1910-1921, of people, images, residences and other buildings, and public functions in the Staunton, Virginia area, developed from original glass-plate negatives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The postive images were developed by Clinton Sisson of the Special Collections Department, Alderman Library, University of Virginia Library, and were given to the Library, on September 24, 1994, by Mr. Sisson.
Scope and Content Information
There are ninety-one photographs, 1910-1921, of people, images, residences and other buildings, and public functions in the Staunton, Virginia area, developed from original glass-plate negatives in the possession of David Schwartz of Staunton, Virginia. The photographer is identified as a Mr. Dow. The photographs are unidentified and an attempt was made to identify categories by using identifying signs in the photographs themselves and by consulting Staunton, Virginia: It's Past, Present and Future by Armistead C. Gordon [F234.S8G6 1890] and Staunton, Virginia: A Pictorial History published by the Historic Staunton Foundation [F234.S8M34 1985].
Contents List
- Augusta Military Academy, Fort Defiance, Virginia ca. 1910-1921
  [cadets in formation, seated in front of institution, and in band]
- Augusta Military Academy, Fort Defiance, Virginia: Sports ca. 1910-1921
  [individuals and team for baseball, basketball, and football]
- Businesses, Staunton, Virginia ca. 1910-1921
  [business district: Farmers and Merchants Bank; The Little Fashion Shop; Standard Motor Gasoline Garage and other garages; pool parlor (interior); commercial vehicles; factory/plant located on railroad; and, sketches of Dow's Electric Light Studio, The New Theatre Keith Vaudeville Daily (circle and orchestra)]
- Disasters, Staunton, Virginia ca. 1910-1921
  [possibly scenes following disasters, 1910-1911, such as the Baldwin Street cave-in and the Johnson Street fire]
- Educational and Religious Facilities, Staunton, Virginia ca. 1910-1921
  [library entrance; [public school] with group of adults and children; [reunion] of the Ten Point School, 1917; church and congregation; baptismal records, 1747-1748]
- Fair Grounds, Staunton, Virginia ca. 1910-1921
  [people, cars, tents, racetrack, playground, picnic at the [Baldwin District Fair] next to Gypsy Hill Park]
- Farming, Staunton, Virginia ca. 1910-1921
  [farmers/farm hands and tractors in fields; butcher]
- Residences, Staunton, Virginia ca. 1910-1921
- Unidentified Persons ca. 1910-1921
  [African-American man; policeman; woman]
- World War I Parade, Staunton, Virginia ca. 1910-1921
  [Augusta Military Academy cadets and marching band; Red Cross vehicles; representatives of the K[ing's] D[aughters] H[ospital] and the S[ ] H[ ] S[ ]; vehicles carrying officials and displaying the American flag; crowds]